Flowers that bloom in the darkness
can only be at ease in the darkness
闇に咲く花は　所詮　闇にしか憩えぬ
Flowers that bloom in the darkness
can only be at ease in the darkness.
散る葩の美しさよ
The beauty of falling flower petals...
されど　莟のまま散らすこともなし
There is no need to let blossoms
fall before they bloom.
はい　お待ちどお様　今日はカレー飯
Here, sorry to keep you waiting.
Today's curry rice.
Wow, Brother.
流石兄様　おいしそう
It looks delicious!
おーそうだ
Oh, right!
いっただきまーす
Thanks!
ソースソース
The sauce, the sauce.
By the way, Brother.
そういえば兄様
昨日港近くのお店で見たバウムクーヘン
Did you buy the baumkuchen cake we saw
yesterday at the store near the harbor?
買ってきてくれました
Oh...
忘れたの
You forgot?
Come on! I told you I must have it today!
もう　云ったでしょう
今日は絶対あれを食べたいって
Oh, sorry.
ごめん
By the way...
ところで…
Is this the cake you meant?
あれって　これ？
もう　兄様ったら　こうしてやる
Oh, Brother.
You're going to get it!
ちょっと　ナオミ
ナオミ　やめて
H-Hey!
Stop!
Ah
Brother...
兄様
Must you work while you eat?
お食事中までお仕事？
市警から聴取記録が届いたんだ　鏡花ちゃんの
I got the interview records
from the city police.
The one with Kyouka-chan.
I heard she was an orphan before
the Port Mafia took her in...
確かポートマフィアに拾われる前は孤児だったって
その孤児になった理由だけど
As for why she became an
orphan in the first place,
ご両親が殺されたんだ
her parents were killed.
The one responsible was...
犯人は…
お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
仕事貰ってきたよ
I got you a case.
その前にこれ　発射式の電撃針
Before that, though, here's a taser.
The Port Mafia's after you, too.
ポートマフィアも狙ってるだろうし　護身用にって
We wanted you to have it for self defense.
まあ　今回危険はないと思うけど
Well, I don't think you'll be in
any danger this time, though.
What kind of job is it?
どんな仕事？
この証拠品の封筒を法廷の判事さんに渡す
You have to deliver this
envelope with evidence
to a judge in court.
And this is the judge.
で　これがその判事さん
Got it.
了解　完全に記憶した
I've memorized his face.
気合入ってるね
You're really into this.
最初の仕事だから？
Is it because it'll be your first job?
違う
No.
最初の仕事は　建物に侵入して二人殺すことだった
My first job was to infiltrate
a building and kill two people.
そうか　彼女はずっと…
I see.
She's always been working.
「夜叉白雪」は殺戮の異能力
Demon Snow is an ability to kill.
他者を殺す時のみ　鏡花は意味を得る
Only when killing someone does
Kyouka's existence have meaning.
I'll do my best.
私…
頑張る
入れない？
We can't go in?
許可が必要です
You need a permit.
でも約束の時間が…
But it's almost time.
Please sign in on that form
and wait until you're called.
そこの手続用紙に記入して　受理まで待ってください
But it's almost time.
約束の時間が
規則ですから
Sorry, it's the rules.
駄目だ　判事さん出ないや
Nope, the judge isn't picking up.
連絡の行き違いみたいだ
I guess there was some miscommunication.
あの警備員さんを何とかしないと
We have to do something about the guard.
You mean get rid of him?
消す？
Huh?
First, I'll use my charms to
lure him into a deserted place,
先ずは色仕掛けで人気のない処に誘い込んでから
ぐさりと
then stab...
探偵社はそういう仕事の進め方はしません
We don't do things like that at the Agency!
Then I only know one other way.
ならあと一つしか方法を知らない
ちょっと　鏡花ちゃん
Hey!
Kyouka-chan?
Authorized
Personnel
Only
Switch Room
Electrical
Transformer
何だ
What the...
What are you doing?
何を…
What's all this racket about?
何事かね　この騒ぎは
A delivery.
お届け物です
Oops.
Got in... a lot of trouble.
Here.
はい
社長が話を付けてくれたよ
The president settled things.
He's friends with the judge.
判事さんとご友人なんだって
停電にするところまではよかったのに
It was going so well up until
the power outage...
そこまではありなんだ
So doing that was fine in your mind?
So you're still holding onto that phone.
その電話　まだ捨ててなかったんだね
I had the service provider
change the program.
業者に指示式を変えてもらったし
It's important to me.
大事な物だから
その　可能性の話なんだけど
About possibilities as we move forward...
もし　君の異能力の謎が解けて
If we can figure out the remaining
unknowns about your ability,
電話の声にしか従わない夜叉を操れるようになれば
and if you can control your Demon Snow
without the voice from the phone,
探偵社の力の一つに…
then you can become an asset to the Agency—
駄目
No!
駄目　夜叉はもう二度と…
No.
I'm never using Demon Snow again.
夜叉白雪よ
Demon Snow,
鏡花に嘘の世界を教える者に罰を与えよ
punish those who teach
Kyouka a world of lies.
害獣の血でも飛沫く様は美しいのう
Though it is the blood of vermin,
it's still beautiful when it splatters.
Ability:
Golden Demon
Port Mafia Executive
Omisaki Kouyou
そうは思わぬかえ
Don't you agree?
My dear Kyouka...
愛しの鏡花や
わっちがどれほどそなたの身を案じ　胸を痛めたか
Do you know how I worried
for you and felt such pain
このような獣畜生どもの許にそなたを残すことになって
that I left you with animals and vermin?
じゃが　もう心配は要らぬぞ
But there is nothing to worry about now.
何も煩うことはない
You need not concern yourself with anything.
わっちが守ってやろうぞ
I will protect you.
She is not going back to the Port Mafia.
彼女はもうポートマフィアには戻らない
彼女の力は探偵社の仕事で振るわれるべきものだ
Her strengths are for her
to use in Agency jobs.
I knew I should have come for you without
waiting for Ougai-dono's permission.
矢張り鷗外殿の許可など待たず　直ぐに迎えに来るべきであった
I cannot let you stay
here for a moment longer
このような偽善の巣にそなたを一秒も置いてはおけぬ
in this festering lair of hypocrisy.
You must have been led astray
by their beguiling words
甘言に唆され　そこが光の世界と勘違いしたのであろう
and mistaken their world
for one full of light.
But they will eventually ask
you to use your Demon Snow.
じゃが奴らはいずれ云うぞ　夜叉白雪を使えと
Let us return to the place where you belong.
さあ　戻るぞ　そなたの居場所へ
Wait.
待て　どこに連れていく
Where are you taking her?
The place where Kyouka-chan belongs...
鏡花ちゃんの居場所は…
探偵社だ
is the Agency!
遅いのう
So slow.
A second demon?
夜叉がもう一体
矢張り仕事を先に済ますかのう
Maybe I'll finish my job first after all.
Die, boy.
くたばれ　小僧
やめて
No!
Ougai-dono wishes all Agency
operatives to be eradicated.
鷗外殿は探偵社員ことごとくの鏖殺を所望じゃ
しかしわっちはそなたの助命を嘆願し　特別に許された
However, I pleaded for
your life to be spared,
and he agreed to make a special exception.
戻るのじゃ　鏡花
Come back, Kyouka.
そなたは闇の花
You are a flower born of darkness.
You will only be at ease in the darkness.
闇の中でしか憩えぬ
違う
No.
I am not a flower of darkness.
私は闇の花じゃない
恨むぞ　小僧
She has been blinded by the light.
あの子は光に目が眩んでおる
貴様が見せた光じゃ
It is a light you showed her.
しかし幸いまだ手はある
But fortunately, all is not lost.
I doubt you would want to stay
if the Agency no longer has him,
小僧なき探偵社はさぞかし居づらかろう
even more so if he is killed because of you.
そなたの所為で殺されたとあらば尚更
わかった
Okay!
I'll come back. So please.
戻ります　だから…
Everything is for you, Kyouka.
凡てはそなたの為じゃ　鏡花
You'll understand someday.
いずれわかる時が来る
How precious you are.
愛いのう
Well done, Kyouka.
流石じゃ　鏡花
まるで殺気を感じなんだ
I did not sense anything from you.
I saw a bright world.
明るい世界を見た
知らなかった頃には　もう戻れない
I cannot go back to a time when
I did not know such a thing existed.
それを使うな　鏡花
Don't use it, Kyouka.
使えばそなたは…
If you use it, you will...
夜叉白雪　私の敵を倒して
Demon Snow, defeat my enemy!
僕のロシナンテ号が…
My Rocinante...
この国の道狭すぎだね
The roads in this country are too narrow.
目的地まで歩くしかない
We'll just have to walk to our destination.
I really want to finish
this so we can go back.
は…早く終わらせて帰りたい
It's been four years since
I was last outside.
外出は４年振りだ
まあいいや
Oh, well!
Let's go.
行こう　「荷物」が届く頃だ
Our luggage is about to arrive.
This blade is your true nature.
この刃がそなたの本性じゃ
邪魔者と見れば直ちに殺す
You kill anyone as soon as you
believe they are in your way.
まるで夜叉じゃ
You are like a demon, yourself.
違う
No!
I can understand why you think that.
そなたの気持ち　わからぬでもない
じゃが闇に咲く花は　闇にしか憩えぬ
But a flower that has
bloomed in the darkness
can only be at ease in the darkness.
何故わっちにわかるか
Why do I know that?
Because there was a woman who
also craved the same light,
同じく光に焦がれて　焼かれて落ちた女が居った故
but was burned by it and
fell into the darkness.
戻れ　鏡花
Come back, Kyouka.
戻りたくない
I don't want to.
それでも　私は…
Despite everything, I still...
目的の為に凡る殺戮を正当化するその本性は変われぬ
You cannot change your true nature.
You justify any killing
to achieve our goals.
If that were not true,
でなくば　そのように夜叉を使える筈がない
you would not be able to
use your demon like so.
After all, your demon...
何故なら夜叉はそなたの両親を…
killed your parents.
惨殺したのだから
That's...
そんな
But why?
どうして
違う　これは…
No, this is...
あやつにはわからんよ
He would not understand.
日の当たる世界に生きる者には
No one who lives in the world of light can.
You no longer have to wield that blade in
search of a place where you can belong.
もう居場所を求めて刃を振り翳さずともよい
I will protect you.
わっちが守ってやる
頭を下げてくださーい
Please duck.
Oh, look how it flies!
飛んだ飛んだ
Are you okay, Atsushi?!
大丈夫か　敦
国木田さん　何故ここに
Kunikida-san... Why are you here?
鏡花の携帯に着信があれば　信号を出すよう手を入れておいた
I modified Kyouka's cell so that it'd
send a signal if anyone called it.
立て
Get up.
いつまで守られ役でいる心算だ
Why're you acting like a damsel in distress?
根性骨が人虎の売りだろう
A weretiger's supposed to be tough!
探偵社の毒虫め
Agency vermin!
鏡花にこれ以上毒の光を見せるな
Don't show Kyouka any more
of your toxic light!
Wow, what great timing.
タイミング最高
It's like the split second
before a collision.
衝突一秒前って感じだ
If we could've come just a bit later,
we would've had it easy.
もう少し遅く来れば楽できたのに
Do you want in?
君やる？
構わないが
I don't care either way,
大勢の視線が痒い
but all the stares are
making me uncomfortable.
Ability:
Grapes of Wrath
Guild Operative
John S
Oh, fine.
仕方ない　ギルドの給料分は仕事しますか
I guess I'll work for my keep for the Guild.
Guild Operative
Lovecraft
Ability:
The Great Old One
I'm tired.
ああ　怠い
ああ　痒い
Ugh, itchy.
Yuck, tired and itchy.
ああ　怠くて痒い
こいつら　ギルドの異能力者か
Are they gifted Guild members?
Oh, keep the middle clear, will you?
あーと　真ん中あけといてね
Our luggage will be arriving soon.
そろそろ「荷物」が届くから
Something's up there!
何かいる
いかん　撃て
No!
Fire!
Episode Seventeen
Three Companies Conflict
Come to think of it...
そういえば　ポオ殿とルイーザ殿はどちらに
Where is Sir Poe and Lady Louisa?
高い処をお恐れあそばしてお残りに
They have a fear of heights,
so they stayed behind.
死ねばいいのに
They should just die.
楽な仕事だったね　牧師殿
That was easy, Reverend.
May God have mercy on the sinful.
罪深き者達に神の恩寵を
Where am I?
ここはどこだ
I think there was an enemy attack...
確か僕は敵にやられて
いい感じの大怪我じゃないか　えぇ　敦
That's quite a superb critical
injury you've got there, Atsushi.
さあ　治療の時間だ
Well, it's time for treatment.
今日はこいつでいこう
I'll use this one today.
いやぁああ
The detectives have fully
recovered, physically.
まったく　腑甲斐ないね
What a helpless lot you are.
妾の能力がなきゃ　今頃揃って土の下だよ
Without my ability,
you'd all be pushing up daisies by now.
How are you all feeling?
工合はどうだ
President...
社長
I'm sorry.
申し訳ありません　俺が付いていながら
I was there, and yet...
よい　少し出る
All good.
I'll be out for a bit.
But isn't it dangerous to go out right now?
でも　今外出するのは危ないんじゃ
He's pretty riled up, from the looks of him.
ありゃ相当鶏冠に来てるね
Hey, Elise-chan...
ねぇ　エリスちゃん　食べ過ぎは体によろしくないよ
Eating that much isn't
good for your health...
Why?
なんで　甘いは正義
Sweetness is justice.
そうだけど…
Well, sure, but...
前にリンタロウが買ってきたドレス　着てあげてもいい
I can consider trying on the dress
you bought me earlier, Rintarou.
Do you want seconds?
おかわり　要る？
Boss, we received word that the
Agency got to the scene ahead of us
首領
我々より早く現場についた探偵社が紅葉の姐さんを連れ去ったとのことです
and took Kouyou away.
We can't take rash action
五大幹部の一翼を人質に取られては
now that one of the top five executives
has been taken hostage.
迂闊に手が
そうだね
Right...
Okay!
よし　探偵社の社長を殺そう
Let's kill the president of the Agency!
I prefer assassination.
暗殺がいいな
外部の殺し屋を使えば　労力もかからず
If we hire outside contractors,
we'll spare ourselves the labor
私達は対ギルドに…
and we can focus on confronting the Guild.
傾注できる
Hey, Sister.
やあ　姐さん
It's been a while.
ご無沙汰
It has indeed been a while, traitor.
確かに久しいのう　裏切者よ
Boy, is Kyouka safe?
童　鏡花は無事かえ
彼女は行方知れずだ
She's missing.
あなたの所為だ
Because of you.
What's so funny?!
何が可笑しい
Leave her to me.
彼女は私に任せたまえ
Dazai-san!
太宰さん
Just leave it, okay?
いいからいいから
却説　早速で悪いけど
Well, then.
Sorry to get right to the point,
ポートマフィアの戦況と今後の作戦あたりから教えてよ
but tell us where the
Port Mafia's at in the conflict
and what your strategy is moving forward.
ポートマフィアの掟を忘れたかえ　坊主
Have you forgotten the
Port Mafia's code, boy?
Those with loose tongues die first.
江戸雀は最初に死ぬ
Your subordinates were marked with a brand
that identified them as torture specialists.
姐さんの部下に拷問専門の班があったよね
稀に彼らが手古摺る相手に助太刀したことがあったけど
On the rare occasion that they ran
into trouble, I would help out...
私が訊いても口を閉ざしたままの捕虜が一人でもいたっけ
Can you recall a single hostage who
didn't talk after I asked the questions?
This is not for the eyes of children.
ここからは大人の時間だね
調査員は全員社屋を発ち　旧晩香堂に参集せよ
All operatives are to leave
the company building
and gather at the former Bankoudou.
Is that the place that used
to be your headquarters
会社設立前に社長が拠点にしていたという晩香堂ですか
before you founded the Agency, President?
Only a select few know of that place.
あの講堂はごく限られた人間しか知らぬ
拠点を秘匿せねば数で勝る敵に圧し潰される
If we cannot keep our location secret,
we'll be crushed by foes
who have superior numbers.
So the president is
prepared to go to war...
社長は矢張り戦争の覚悟を
ご訪客のようだ
I seem to have visitors.
President?
社長　どうされました
What's the matter?
社長
President?
What's wrong?
どうしたんです
社長との通話が…
The call with the president just...
Could it be an enemy attack?
敵襲か
What?
なら早く救援に
Then we should go help right away!
社長は大丈夫　それより…
The president is fine.
More importantly—
なんでわかるんです　そんなことを
How do you know that for sure?!
俺の手を掴んでみろ
Try to grab my hand.
すぐわかる
You'll figure it out right away.
師匠から最初に教わった技だ
That's the first technique
I learned from my master.
I've never won a single match against him.
俺は未だに師匠から一本も取れん
He's not going to lose to a group
of dime-a-dozen assassins.
十把一絡げの刺客にあの人が負ける筈がない
Go back to your master and
tell him, "good try."
戻って主に告げよ
「よき心掛けだ」と
「狙うならば　今後も私のみ狙え」
Continue to target me and me alone!
お見事
Well done.
探偵社は事務所を捨てて　別の施設に隠れたようです
It seems the Agency has abandoned their office
and hidden in a different facility.
新拠点の検出は困難ですね
It will be difficult to
find their new location.
ポートマフィアも動き出しました
The Port Mafia have begun to
make their move, as well.
When I was a boy...
少年の頃　これと同じ銃を買うのに二年働いたが
I worked for two years to
buy a gun like this,
それでも足りずに四人殺した
but I still couldn't save enough,
so I killed four men.
今ではこの銃を作る会社も俺のものだ
Now, I own the company that makes this gun.
金は悪夢だ
Money is a nightmare.
Every time you obtain something you desire,
欲しい物が一つ手に入る度　欲しい物が一つ減る
you lose something you desire.
Eventually, the world becomes as tiresome
as blue smoke rising from burning leaves.
やがて世界は枯れ葉を燃やす青い煙のように
退屈になる
That's why, John...
だからね　ジョン君
my world is so bright right now.
俺の世界は今　輝きに満ちているのだよ
あの街は必ず俺が手に入れる
That city will be mine.
Listen, all.
皆聞け
社の鏖殺を謀るポートマフィア
The Port Mafia seeks to
eradicate the Agency.
社の簒奪を目論むギルド
The Guild seeks to usurp the Agency.
We must protect the Agency
from these two foes.
この両雄より　探偵社を守らねばならぬ
太宰　説明を
Dazai, explain.
Yes, sir.
はーい
The Guild has substantial financial assets,
ギルドは資金力　ポートマフィアは頭数に優れます
and the Port Mafia has
the numerical advantage.
そこで我々は人員を攻勢と守勢に分けて
So, we will split into defensive
and offensive teams
奇襲戦法で姑息に抗います
and engage in guerrilla tactics.
守勢の要は何といっても　ここで与謝野先生を守ること
The critical goal for the defense
is to protect Yosano-sensei here.
Defensive Team: Fukuzawa, Ranpo, Yosano, Kenji
先生の治癒能力があれば　死なない限り全快できます
With her healing ability,
as long as we don't die outright,
we will be cured of any injury.
Offensive Team A
Kunikida, Tanizaki
そして攻勢は二組に分割
The offense will split into two teams,
谷崎君の隠密能力と私の異能力無効化で　敵の横合いを叩く
and surprise the enemy using
Tanizaki-kun's subterfuge ability
Offensive Team B
Dazai, Atsushi
and my nullification ability.
この戦の肝要は　この拠点を隠匿することです
The crux of this strategy is to keep
our base of operations hidden.
総出でここに雪崩込まれると…
If our enemies were to hit us
here with everything they have,
our defense would not hold.
守勢が保ちませんから
Boss, our assault ended in failure.
首領　襲撃は失敗です
We've put a tail on him, but I suspect...
尾行はつけてありますが　恐らくは…
いいよ　予定通りだ
Very well.
It's all according to plan.
それで　刺客の服に付けた放射性追跡元素は
And?
What about the radioactive tracking element
we put on the assassins' clothes?
We're getting a strong signal.
反応は良好です
That's the Agency's secret hiding place.
そこが探偵社の隠れ家だ
三組織のうち　生き残るのは一組織だけだ
Only one of the three
organizations can survive.
闘う以外に活路はない
Our only course of action is to fight!
勿論　最後に残るのは我々だ
Of course, we'll be the ones left standing.
結末が今から楽しみだよ
I'm looking forward to the results.
三組織　異能力戦争だ
It'll be a three-way gifted war!
Episode Eighteen
エリスちゃん　お描きがしたいなら　そんな小さな画用紙じゃなくて
この部屋の壁一面に描けばいい
お描きも人生も作戦も枠に収まっていては面白くないんだから
あ　いいことを思いついた
敵に手紙を書こう
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第十八話
The strategy of conflict
でも医療用メスでダーツするのは正直結構難しい